<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cloud on Olivia Snowden&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cloud on Olivia Snowden&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BUILDING LOAD BALANCERS</title>
      <link>/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/test/</guid>
      <description>What is a Load Balancer? Load balancers are networking resources that take in network traffic through their frontend and distribute that traffic to their backend(s). Load balancers have a few general attributes:
  Frontend Where clients reach the load balancer, the &amp;ldquo;face&amp;rdquo; of the load balancer.
  Backend The server(s) where the load balancer directs traffic
  Forwarding Rules The logic the load balancer uses to distribute traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COGNITIVE SERVICES-TRANSLATING SPEECH</title>
      <link>/cognitive-services-translation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 16:41:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cognitive-services-translation/</guid>
      <description>In addition to text analysis Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s cognitive services allow you to convert speech to text, text to speech, and even translate between spoken languages. This powerful AI service is surprisingly easy to use. I was able to speak into my computers microphone and receive a text translation in one language or a spoken translation in multiple languages &amp;ndash;all with the code provided on Microsoft Learn. You have the option to work with the speech SDK (software development kit) in C# or python, I choose python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COGNITIVE SERVICES-SENTIMENT IN TEXT</title>
      <link>/cognitive-services-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 18:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cognitive-services-text/</guid>
      <description>As I continue to study artificial intelligence I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to practice using Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s cognitive services. I was first introduced to cognitive services during the virtual Microsoft Build 2020 conference, and I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed getting to use them for myself. Since creating and training your own artificial intelligence/machine learning software is all kinds of complicated, cognitive services allow anyone to use AI in their projects without having to write much code. All you have to do is call the service that you want, and it will do the hard work for you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
